## M. Tabish Tariq

## Software Engineer

## tmtabish@gmail.com | +923074331961

Github: /TabishTariq LinkedIn: /in/mtabishtariq

## **Summary**

I am a full stack developer having 3 years of experience in software development with MERN & ROR, seeking a position where I can utilize my professional skills in career opportunities. I am an outgoing high energy person and want to do work for my safe future.

I want to continue my career working in MERN stack

#### **Skills**

**Languages**: Javascript/Typescript, Ruby.

**Frameworks**: React JS, React Native, Node JS, Express JS, ROR.

Other: Redux, MySQL, Git, Git Actions, AWS, SAAS, Multi Tenant Apps.

## **Experiences**

# **7Vals (2 Years) Software Engineer**

Lahore Pakistan August 2022 - Present

- Working on ROR based web app by creating new features, handling and creating secure APIs for the mobile App.
- Creating reusable components in React Native mobile app and implementing new features
- Worked on EZOfficeinventory, EZO-CMMS, EZRentals

## DIT GCU (1 Year) MERN Stack Developer

Lahore Pakistan October 2021 – August 2022

- Working on GCU Hostel System, GCU HRM System
- Client requirement gathering
- Server side management & deployments
- Creating and developing software using ReactJS, ExpressJS, MySql, NodeJs

#### **Education**

BachelorsGCU LahoreBSCS (Hons)CGPA: 3.582018-2022(3rd Position)

#### **Courses**

- Advanced JavaScript	Udemy – 25.5 Hours
- NodeJS Advanced Concepts	Udemy – 16 Hours
- Blockchain A-Z	Udemy – 14.5 Hours
- AWS: Cloud Practitioner	Udemy – 15 Hours
- Microservices with NodeJS & ReactJS	Udemy – 54.5 Hours
Initiatives	

### 7Vals

## - Implemented Husky For Automation

Implemented husky to prevent code push if any TS error occurs or any cyclic dependency exist on the code. It helps our code to be error free and prevent any cyclic dependencies to be pushed to the git repository

#### - Use React With Rails

Currently at 7vals, our product was implemented using simple html, css and javascript. They were not using any fronted framework and it was difficult to migrate that big product into React. I took the initiative to implement react with rails and migrate rails pages into rails. It helped better user experience throughout the product

#### References

References Available on Request.